<Skill>
  <Name>Disable Device</Name>
  <AbilityType>Dexterity</AbilityType>
  <TrainedOnly>true</TrainedOnly>
  <ArmorCheckPenalty>true</ArmorCheckPenalty>
  <Description>You are skilled at disarming traps and opening locks. In addition, this skill lets you sabotage simple mechanical devices, such as catapults, wagon wheels, and doors.</Description>
  <Check>&lt;h1&gt;Check&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When disarming a trap or other device, the Disable Device check is made secretly, so that you don't necessarily know whether you've succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The DC depends on how tricky the device is. If the check succeeds, you disable the device. If it fails by 4 or less, you have failed but can try again. If you fail by 5 or more, something goes wrong. If the device is a trap, you trigger it. If you're attempting some sort of sabotage, you think the device is disabled, but it still works normally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You also can rig simple devices such as saddles or wagon wheels to work normally for a while and then fail or fall off some time later (usually after 1d4 rounds or minutes of use).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Device&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Disable Device DC*&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Example&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Simple&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 round&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="white-space:normal;"&gt;Jam a lock&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="even"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Tricky&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1d4 rounds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="white-space:normal;"&gt;Sabotage a wagon wheel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Difficult&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2d4 rounds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="white-space:normal;"&gt;Disarm a trap, reset a trap&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="even"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Extreme&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2d4 rounds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="white-space:normal;"&gt;Disarm a complex trap, cleverly sabotage a clockwork device&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tfoot&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan="4"&gt;* If you attempt to leave behind no trace of your tampering, add 5 to the DC.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tfoot&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class="right"&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Lock Quality&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Disable Device DC&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Simple&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="even"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Average&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="odd"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Good&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="even"&gt;&lt;td&gt;Superior&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open Locks&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p id="open-locks"&gt;The DC for opening a lock depends on its quality. If you do not have a set of thieves' tools, these DCs increase by 10.&lt;/p&gt;</Check>
  <Action>&lt;p&gt;The amount of time needed to make a Disable Device check depends on the task, as noted above. Disabling a simple device takes 1 round and is a full-round action. A tricky or difficult device requires 1d4 or 2d4 rounds. Attempting to open a lock is a full-round action.&lt;/p&gt;</Action>
  <TryAgain>&lt;p&gt;Varies. You can retry checks made to disable traps if you miss the check by 4 or less. You can retry checks made to open locks.&lt;/p&gt;</TryAgain>
  <Special>&lt;p&gt;If you have the Deft Hands feat, you get a bonus on Disable Device checks (see Feats).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rogue who beats a trap's DC by 10 or more can study the trap, figure out how it works, and bypass it without disarming it. A rogue can rig a trap so her allies can bypass it as well.&lt;/p&gt;</Special>
  <Restriction>&lt;p&gt;Characters with the trapfinding ability (like rogues) can disarm magic traps. A magic trap generally has a DC of 25 + the level of the spell used to create it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The spells &lt;i&gt;fire trap&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;glyph of warding&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;symbol&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;teleportation circle&lt;/i&gt; also create traps that a rogue can disarm with a successful Disable Device check. &lt;i&gt;Spike growth&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;spike stones&lt;/i&gt;, however, create magic hazards against which Disable Device checks do not succeed. See the individual spell descriptions for details.&lt;/p&gt;</Restriction>
  <Untrained />
</Skill>